Curriculum Vitae

Kenneth Rohde Christiansen

Address

Westerhavenstraat 12a 9718 AL Groningen The Netherlands

Nationality Danish (Jutish)

Day of birth June 6th, 1979

My main interest is working with state of the art, innovative software, preferable in an open-source environment. I am also very interested in usability and machine-human interaction and have therefore earlier worked with the GNOME project on various projects. The last couple of years I haven't done much open-source programming due to concentrating on my studies and developing minor web services. I would, though, very much like to make a comeback in the open-source world and would especially like to work with GNOME related projects.

I am a quick learner who pays special interest in the things that I am working on. I perform well in teams, but can also work well on my own which was confirmed by my internship at IFIS¹ in Germany:

"In jouw geval denk ik dat een hoog cijfer volkomen terecht is. Ik denk zelfs dat de beoordeling, in vergelijking met andere stages, zelfs aan de lage kant is. De beoordeling door Ulrich Zukowski [IFIS] en mijn persoonlijke beoordeling van het stageverslag laten voldoende vrijheid om een totaaloordeel 9.5 te geven." [Rody Moddemeijer, University of Groningen]

Translated:

"In your case I am certain that a high grade is indeed appropriate. I even think that the grading is on the low edge compared to other internships. The grading done by Ulrich Zukowski [IFIS] and my personal grading gives me the freedom to give you a final score of 9.5 [out of 10; 10 being the best]." [Rody Moddemeijer, University of Groningen]

Education

1985-1996 Nordre Folkeskole, Bramming (Primary school)

1996-1997 Ribe Commercial College, Ribe (High School part 1)

¹ IFIS (http://www.ifis-passau.de) is a company specialised in developing Enterprise Web Applications within the field of Knowledge Management, e-Learning and Workflow Management. One of their most known applications is the IFIS Assessment. Suite, which enables easy development of interactive learning environments, exercises, and online/offline examinations. The application is used by some large clients as for instance the German railway company Die Bahn, who have fully redesigned their train driver education and based it on the Assessment. Suite. Most of the applications developed at IFIS are build using open standards and open-source software from the Apache family.

1997-1999	Ribe Commercial College, Ribe (High School part 2)
1999-2000	High School supplement - GSK (HF), ${f VUC\ Lyngby}$ 3 additional courses: Physics B + A level, Chemistry B level
2000-2004	University of Copenhagen ; Bachelor education. Major: Computer Science (CS). Minor: Mathematics. Additional, I have earned 80 ETCS points in Dutch and related languages (Afrikaans, Old Low Franconian, etc)
2003	Summer Course Dutch language and culture (by the Nederlandse taalunie), Zeist (the Netherlands)
2004	University of Groningen; Master education Computer Science: Software Engineering

Work experience

2005	RUG	Speaker at the StudColl Conference 2005, Groningen, with the speech "A look at Programming Methods for solving problems of current Software Development"
2004	Gyldendal/Prisma	Co-worker on the Danish-Dutch/Dutch-Danish Dictionary
1999-2002	GNOME Project	Translator from English to Danish, co-organizer of the GNOME Translation Project
1998-2004	GNOME Project	Programmer (intltool, GnomeMeeting, Rhythmbox, etc)
2000-2001	GNOME Project	Main organizer of the GNOME User and Developer European Conference 2001 congress, Copenhagen (Denmark)
2002	GNOME Project	Speaker at the GNOME User and Developer European Conference 2002 congress, Seville (Spain)
2004	DKUUG	Co-organizer of the NORDU 2004 UNIX/BSD conference (www.nordu.org), Copenhagen (Denmark)
1995-1999	Helle Swimming Club	Life Guard (indoors and at the beach)
1995-1999	Helle Swimming Club	Swimming instructor
2000	PCPlanet	Technical Columnist
2000-2004	Alt om DATA	Technical Columnist
2004-2005	People's University of Leeuwarden, NL	Teacher in Danish language and culture.
2005	IFIS (Germany)	Internship working on the Enterprise Web product IFIS Assessment. Suite developed for Deutsche Bahn and the University of Passau

Language knowledge

English, German, Danish, Norwegian, Swedish, Dutch, Afrikaans and Low Saxon

At intermediate level

Portuguese, Spanish and Frisian

Computer knowledge/experience

Programming languages and tools

C, C++ Perl, PHP Java, C# SML

JavaScript/ECMAScript

GNU autotools; automake, M4, etc. (Programming mostly done under Linux)

Operation System Environments

DOS, OS/2 Warp, BeOS, MacOS X, Windows and various Linux varieties such as Red Hat, Ubuntu, Mandrake and Novell/SUSE.

Programming fields

Advanced algorithms and data structures

Object Oriented design, UML

Operation Systems (Kernel design)

Embedded Systems

Networking

Image Processing

Pattern Matching

Computer Vision

2- and 3-Dimensional Graphics

Geometric Algorithms, Triangulations

Ray tracing

Scientific Visualization

Compiler design

Computer Organization and Design (CPU design)

Databases (SQL, MySQL, PosgreSQL etc.) HTML, XML, SGML, Docbook, XSLT, CSS

Colloquium (Learning to write scientific papers and giving speeches)

Computational Science Machine Translation

Web Services based on J2EE, Hibernate, Tomcat, Struts, and related technologies.

Various

1995	Swimming: Course in time measurement	
1995	Swimming: Education as help instructor	
1995	Swimming: Education as basic instructor	
1996-1997	Swimming: Education as (full) instructor, module I, II, III, IV	
1997	Swimming: Finish-, turn- and heap judge	
1997	First Aid Course by Red Cross, Denmark	
1997-1999	Life Guard courses and test every year for 3-4 years	
1999	Esbjerg Commercial College, Esbjerg (2 additional Computer Science courses)	
1999	University of Oxford, Young Enterprise Examination	